SAMMY SAMKOUGH

862-239-0100 | sammysamkough@gmail.com | Wayne, NJ 07470

https://sammy.pizza | https://github.com/ssamkough | https://linkedin.com/in/ssamkough

AI TECHNOLOGY TECHNOLOGY AND AUTOMATION ENGINEER; BENJAMIN MOORE

SUMMARY:

Software Engineer with over five years of diverse experience building for the web, specializing in AI automation.

Creating automation solutions using latest developments in AI and machine learning technologies.

Areas of Expertise: GENERATIVE AI // SERVERLESS TECHNOLOGIES // AUTOMATION TECHNOLOGIES

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:

- Languages HTML; CSS; JavaScript; TypeScript; Python; C#; Java; SQL
- Frameworks React.js; Next.js; Angular.js; TensorFlow; PyTorch; sci-kit-learn; Node.js; React Native
- <u>Applications</u> Git; PostgreSQL; Azure; AWS; Google Cloud; Vercel; Firebase; GraphQL; Storybook

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Bonny Systems, New York City, NY; Wayne, NJ

Oct 2023 - Present

Founding Engineer

- Automated calendar event creation by detecting objects / text on physical calendar and translating it to digital events leading to a 70% decrease when creating events using PyTorch, YOLO, and OCR models.
- Achieving over 80% reduction in website load times by improving core web vitals which includes minimizing JavaScript usage, image optimization, and adherence to web standards.

Canal, San Francisco, CA; New York City, NY

May 2021 - Jul 2023

Software Engineer

- Restructured web application search utilizing the OpenAI API to find most relevant products leading to a significant decrease in search queries by over 80%.
- Developed and refined the onboarding process to adapt to evolving user needs, utilizing React, Next.js, TypeScript, XState, Django and GraphQL which lead to an overall 40% increase in user satisfaction.
- Collaborated with a design / product team of five to create our own in-house design system that replaced the Shopify Polaris design system which led to an increase of development speed by over 60%.
- Led the standardization of UI component testing within the in-house design system, significantly reducing component-specific bugs by over 70% using Chromatic and Storybook.

Popstar, Remote USA

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021

Software Engineer

- Launched a feature-rich iOS application using Swift and Firebase / NoSQL, which offered an elegant vertical video experience, including social interactions such as sharing and commenting on videos.
- Engineered personal shop recommendations based on video and user activity using TensorFlow leading to a 40% increase in e-commerce sales.

Decusoft, Hybrid (Ramsey, NJ; Remote USA)

May 2019 - Oct 2020

Full Stack Software Developer

- Implemented several top requested features such as table filtering and sorting using JavaScript, C# and SQL.
- Optimized complex SQL queries which increased the load time performance of the main table interface by 50%.

EDUCATION:

Montclair State University, Montclair, NJ

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science 2019